Sambhaji Murdare

7499533902 | murdaresambhaji4@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/sambhaji-murdare/

PROFILE

Experienced Computer Engineer specialized in Python programming and Software Development with a focus on Object-Oriented Programming. Proficient in Python, HTML, CSS, MySQL, and Git within Linux environments. Three years of Python experience and also committed to ongoing learning and innovation in tech trends.

EDUCATION

Sinhgad Institute of Technology and Science, Pune

B.E. - Computer Science and Engineering - CGPA - 7.75

2019-2023 | Pune-India

Courses: Operating Systems, cyber security, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Databases, Artificial Intelligence, Software Testing and Quality Assurance, Networking, Software Project Management, Machine Learning, Web Development

SKILLS

Languages: Python, HTML, CSS, OOP, SQL

Frameworks - libraries: Django, Pandas, NumPy, Requests, BeautifulSoup, streamlit, PIL, OpenCV, CNN, **Developer Tools - Platforms**: Git, MySql, VS Code, Visual Studio, PyCharm, GitHub, Linux, Vim, Terminal **Soft Skills**: Time Management, Leadership, Collaboration, Effective Communication, Adaptability, Creativity **Others**: Development, API, Problem Solving, Web Scraping, OOPs Concepts, Cyber security, Machine Learning, AI

EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer

Jan 2023 - Dec 2023

hashtrix technologies pvt ltd

Pune | India

- Built various tools for internal use and work on various projects based on Web App, Machine Learning, AI, NLP. Solved some errors
- Work with the adaptive and responsible team. Get connected with them by GitHub to marge my tasks with the team.
- Hands-on experience with Python, Version Control, Libraries, Development Tools, ML Models. Write efficient, reusable and reliable code to build applications, software, or scripts. This may involve using various Python libraries and frameworks.

Python Developer (Intern)

Jun 2022 - Dec 2022

hashtrix technologies pvt ltd

Pune | India

- · Start working with Python and their Libraries, Tools, methodology, Company workflow, Git, GitHub.
- Contribute myself on ongoing projects by writing code snippets, assisting with testing, and providing support to the development team. Also work on smaller features, modules or components under the guidance of experienced developers.
- Always updated with the latest trends, tools, and best practices in Python development to enhance my skills and contribute effectively to projects.

PROJECTS

SMART VOICE ASSISTANT

Technologies: Python, Pyttsx3, Requests, AI, API, Python Libraries

- We all know about Siri, Alex this project is also similar with them with extra features and some hardware parts to make them more useful in our daily life routine.
- Connected with Ardino to get control on hardware to control home ecosystems.

FOOD CALORIES DETECTION

Technologies: Python, Machine Learning, Pandas, Numpy, Streamlit, PIL, BeautifulSoup, Requests, Al

• To detect food type by using Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) for To estimate food weight and calories of food

CERTIFICATES

- Introduction to Programming Using Python | Credential ID 7EBC60198E29
- Introduction to Programming Using HTML and CSS | Credential ID E9D6CFFA953B
- Developing SQL Databases | Credential ID AA3E6549963E